McKersie, Robert B., Files /4033
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert B. McKersie Files
1965-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
McKersie, Robert B.
/4033
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Collection of magazines, reports, letters, and correspondence.
3084855
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 29, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 22, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Robert B. McKersie, DBA
Professor of Management, Emeritus, Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Robert McKersie is professor emeritus of management at the MIT Sloan School of Management, where he has been since 1980. Prior to his time at MIT, he served as dean of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, and as a faculty member of the Graduate School of Business at the University of Chicago. McKersie has served on several presidential commissions at the national level, is a member of the National Academy of Arbitrators, and was president of the National Industrial Relations Research Association (now the Labor and Employment Relations Association). He is the author of numerous articles relating to human resources, industrial relations, and operations management.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4343: Robert B. McKersie Collections /4054: ILR School Dean's Office Additional Files /4071: Robert B. McKersie Additional Files /5464: U.S. Economic Stabilization Program Records
McKersie, Robert B.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Administration.
3084855
- Personnel Magazine Dec. '67, April '69. Personnel Management Magazine Sept. '69, Feb., Apr. '70, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Personnel Management Magazine July, Aug., Nov. '70, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Personnel Management Magazine: Dec. '70, Oct., Nov. '71, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 1, 2, 5, 8, 19, 23, 24, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 29, 36, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 39, 40, 42, 49, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 50, 65, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 79, 83, 92, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 120, 122, 123, 128, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 129, 143, 149, 151, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 152, 155, 161, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Report No. 161 (Supplemental), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- United Kingdom National Board for Prices and Income: Reports No. 169, 170 (Supplemental), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- UK Industrial Courts Act of 1919: Reports on Various Disputes, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- UK Industrial Courts Act of 1919 Reports on Disputes at Rootes Motor Limited and the Port Talbot Works of the British Steel Corporation, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- UK Commission on Industrial elations Reports No. 10, 11, 18-20, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- UK Commission on Industrial Relations Report No. 22, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- UK Ministry of Labor Reports on Disputes, Report of Committee Appointed by Post Office and Union of Post Office Workers, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission vs. American Telephone and Telegraph Company (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Daily Labor Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and Interstate Commerce Commission Related News Clippings and Other Papers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Preliminary Finding s of Fact on AT&T, Memos, and Equal Employment Opportunities Enforcement Act of 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Notes and News Regarding the Executive Office of the President Pay Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Executive Office of the President Pay Board, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Letters, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Cases Potentially Challengeable by Pay Board, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Pay Board Weekly Status Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Statement by George Boldt before Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, Report: Dead Horse and the Featherbird, New York State Human Rights Law, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Staff Report of the President's Panel on Federal Compensation, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Survey of Professional, Administrative, Technical, and Clerical Pay, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Report on the Fiscal 1976 Pay Increase Under the Federal Statutory Pay Systems, Comparability of the Federal Statutory Pay Systems with Private Enterprise Pay Rates, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Federal Employees Pay Council (Established Under Public Law No. 91-656), Comments for Inclusion in Report of the President's Agent, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Statements by Clyde M. Webber to Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, President's Panel on Federal Compensation, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Message from the President of the United States Transmitting A Federal Pay Comparability Alternative Plan, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- News Regarding Pay and Wage Controversies, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters, Correspondence, and Memoranda, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Appendix: Analysis of Methods of Describing the General Schedule Workforce (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Notes (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Memoranda and Letters, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Reports and Papers on Pay/Wage Disputes, 1965-1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- FEPC Decision Documents, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Report to the President's Agent on Pay Rate Determination, U.S. Civil Service Commission, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Typed Notes and Data/Figures Regarding Pay/Wage Dispute, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Options with Respect to the Fiscal 1973 Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Advisory Committee on Federal Pay Repot on Fiscal 1973 Adjustment in Federal Pay, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Messages from the President of the US on An Alternative Plan Postponing Adjustments in Federal Statutory Pay Systems, the Annual Comparison of Federal Salaries in the Statutory Pay Systems to Salaries Paid in Private Enterprise, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- National Association of Internal Revenue Employees vs. Richard M. Nixon, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Federal Pay Comparability Act of 1970, Economic Stabilization of 1970, Amended in 1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous Reports and News Clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Notes (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Memoranda and Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Transcripts of Proceedings: President's Advisory Committee on Federal Pay Tuesday Sept. 12th, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Transcript of Proceedings: President's Advisory Committee on Federal Pay Wednesday Sept. 13th, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- News Clippings and Miscellaneous Reports and Figures, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- The Fiscal 1974 Adjustment in Federal Pay, Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- National Survey of Professional, Administrative, Technical, and Clerical Pay, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Progress Report of HRB-AASHO Joint Committee on Maintenance and Operations Personnel, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Wages and Turnover in the Federal Government- George J. Borjas, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- National Survey of Professional, Administrative, Technical, and Clerical Pay, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- H.R. 13, 10700 Federal Employee Labor- Management Act of 1973 and Federal Service Labor- Management Act of 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Messages from the President of the US Reporting on the Comparability Adjustment for Federal Statutory Pay Systems, the Annual Comparison of Federal Salaries with Those of Private Enterprises, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Report of the Commission on Executive, Legislative, and Judicial Salaries, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Letters and Memoranda, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Statements by Webber, Whitney, Connery, and Wolkomir, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- McKersie Draft of Second Annual Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay and of Personal Objections to Report, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- First Draft: The Fiscal 1974 Adjustment in Federal Pay, Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Notes and Figures (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Draft Reports, Letters, Memoranda, Press Releases, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- News Clippings, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Daily Labor Reports and Miscellaneous Papers, Drafts, and Proposals, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Memoranda and Notes, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Survey of Compensation Practices and the Use of Comparisons in Workplace Wage Determination, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- FEPC Minutes of Meeting, August 14th, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Reports on the Fiscal 1976 Pay Increase Under the Federal Statutory Pay Systems- Annual Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Report to the President of the President's Panel on Federal Compensation, Wage Chronology: Federal Employees Under the General Schedule Pay System, July '24- Oct. '74, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Documents Relating to October 1975 Federal Pay Adjustments, Government Wage Differentials by Sharon P. Smith (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Draft of Report on Comparability of the Federal Statutory Pay Systems with Private Enterprise Pay Rates, Joint Annual Repot by OMB and US Civil Service Commission, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Federal Employees Pay Council Prefatory Remarks and Report on Some Subject, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Comparability of the Federal Statutory Pay Systems with Private Enterprise Pay Rates, Joint Annual Repot by OMB and US Civil Service Commission, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Report on the Fiscal 1977 Pay Increase Under the Federal Statutory Pay Systems, Annual Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Executive Order 11941: Adjustments of Certain Rates of Pay and Allowances, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Sources of Federal Employment and Compensation Data (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Staff Technical Paper- Report on the Occupational Representativeness on the PATC Survey- US Civil Service Commission, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- News Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Notes and Figures (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Letters, Memoranda and Related Reports, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Memoranda and Reports, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- The Fiscal 1975 Adjustment In Federal Pay: Report of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Comparability of the Federal Statutory Pay Systems with Private Enterprise Pay Rates- Joint Annual Report by OMB and US Civil Service Commission, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- The Fiscal 1975 Adjustment In Federal Pay- Repot of the Advisory Committee on Federal Pay, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Report to the Congress by the Comptroller General of the US: Critical Need for a Better System for Adjusting Top Executive, Legislative, and Judicial Salaries, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- "A Case for an Increase in Federal Judicial Salaries in 1974" and The Government Standard from Nov. '74 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Message from the President of the US on his Repot on the Comparability Adjustment for the Federal Statutory Pay Systems, national Survey of Professional, Administrative, Technical, and Clerical Pay, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- News Clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- US Civil Service Commission Letter on Comparable Federal Pay Schedules, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Notes and Figures, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Letters and Memoranda, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Notes, Figures and Meeting Minutes Summary ('74), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Statements of the Government Employees Council, Rick Galleher, Clyde Webber, Dennis Garrison, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Report on the Effect of Deviations between the Payline Adopted for Federal Pay Increases and the Line of "Best Fit" 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Drafts of the Third Report of the President's Advisory Committee on Federal Pay and Related Material, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Report for the President's Advisory Committee on Federal Pay- Survey of White-Collar Pay Adjustments in Private Industry, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- A Bill Recommended to Amend Title 5, United States Code "Federal Salary Comparability Act of 1970" Analysis, Statement of Purpose and Justification (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Congressional Record: Senate and House, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Economic Stabilization Act of 1970, Amended 1971, Federal Pay Comparability Act of 1970 and the Federal Comparability Process, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Comparability of the Federal Statutory Pay Systems with Private Enterprise Pay Rates, Joint Annual Report by OMB and Civil Service Commission, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Report to Congress by Comptroller General on Improvements Needed in the Survey of Non-Federal Salaries Used As Basis for Adjusting Federal White- Collar Salaries, national Survey of Professional, Administrative, Technical, and Clerical Pay, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Message from the President Reporting on Comparability Adjustment and the Annual Comparison of Federal Salaries with the Salaries Paid in Private Enterprise and Conference Report Submitted by Mr. Dulski, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Hearings before the Subcommittee on Compensation of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service on H.R. 18403 and H.R. 18603, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Background of the Federal Pay Comparability Act of 1970 and Federal Pay Developments, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Study of Private Enterprise Pay Rates for Positions Equivalent to GS-14/18- US Civil Service Commission, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Notes (Box 3, Folder 41)
- The Federal Professional Association Newsletter Vol. XII No. 7 "FPA Supports Legislation to Raise Pay Ceilings", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- News Clippings and Press Releases, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Letters and Memoranda, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Letters and Memoranda, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Howard E. Aldrich: "The Impact of Small Businesses on the Urban Environment: Ownership and Employment", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- A.G. Bush Library The University of Chicago Bibliography for "Black Capitalism" and Supplemental Bibliography, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Minority Groups and Business Series, Reprints from Harvard Business Review, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "The Rochester Business Opportunities Corporation"- Charles R. Lincoln, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Foundation Involvement in Minority Business Enterprise, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Feasibility Study for Black Economic Development Cedar Rapids, Iowa 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The United Builders Association of Chicago- Pamphlet (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Minority Group Managers: What's Wrong with Opportunities in Business?"- Israel Unterman, Chicago Merit Employment Committee Newsletter: Youth Motivation- with the Black Businessmen's Touch, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Grad School of Business Indiana University: The Frustrated Black Worker, Prospects for Black Businessmen: Alternative Strategies for Education and Development- Howard Sulkin, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Daily Labor Reports, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- News Clippings, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence and Letters, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- "Profiles in Community Bases Economic Development," "The Bureaucratic Noose"- Geoffrey Faux (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Working Paper 70: Pilot Study of the Impact of Minority Banks on Their Communities by Samuel I. Doctors, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- SBA Data Study for the President's Council on Minority Business Enterprise, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- "Try Us." National Minority Business Directory, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Working Paper Grad School of Management Northwestern University: Evaluation Strategy for a Social Action Program: The Opportunity Funding Corporation- Samuel I. Doctors and Andrew C. Gordon (Box 4, Folder 18)
- A Proposal to the North Lawndale Economic Development Corporation to Provide Training in Management for Its Administrative Trainees b The Graduate School of Management Northwestern University, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Neighborhood Development Corporation: A Business Proposal, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- US Department of Commerce Publication: Outlook- News from the Office of Minority Business Enterprise, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Letters, Comments and "Black Entrepreneurship and Management- A Need for Reliable Information", 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Memoranda, The Review of Black Political Economy, "Management and Technical Assistance for Minority Enterprise- Some Guidelines for the Design and Implementation of the President's Program"- Doctors and Juris, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- McKersie's Comments on "An Econometric Study of Black Capitalism"- Bates, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- "The Potential of Ghetto Development"- Vietorisz and Harrison, Secretary Stans' Presentation- "Comprehensive Minority Enterprise Program for the Future, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Minority Enterprise and Expanded Ownership: Blueprint for the '70s, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- An Economic Development Plan for Kenwood- Oakland, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Business and the Development of Ghetto Enterprise- The Conference Board ('71), Draft Final Report Evaluation of the Public Service Work Opportunities Program ('72), 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- "The Impact of the Civil Rights Act, Title VII, on Female Employees," "Poverty in an Affluent Society"- Mary Jean Bowman (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Remarks by Andrew Brimmer "An Economic Agenda for Black Americans," "Entrepreneurship and Black Economic Development"- McKersie for Conference on Research on Urban Poverty, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- "The Effect of Civil Disorders on Small Business in the Inner City"- Aldrich and Reiss ('70), "Independence Bank of Chicago"- Alphonse Hill ('67), 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- National Advisory Council on Minority Business Enterprise- Summary and Recommendations, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- "The Economic Potential of Black Capitalism"- Brimmer and Terrell, "My Days with Harlem Barbeque Sauce," "Black Capitalism in Ghetto Supermarkets: Problems and Prospects"- Bloom, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- News Clippings, "The New Business of Business"- Cohn, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 35)
- DLR, Bibliographies, and Address by Samuel R. Pierce, Jr. to Houston Real Estate Association- "Black Banks Revisited", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- National Advisory Council for Minority Business Enterprise- Task Force on Business Opportunities: Proceedings July 21st, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- National Advisory Council on Minority Business Enterprise- Task Force on Business Opportunities Subcommittee on Construction July 22nd, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- "Sears in Latin America," "More Minorities in Retailing (Box 5, Folder 3)
- National Advisory Council for Minority Business Enterprise Task Force on Business Opportunities (Box 5, Folder 4)
- National Advisory Council on Minority Business Enterprise: Summary and Recommendations Draft #3 and Outline, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Comments Concerning Table I (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Notes and Misc. Tables (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Memoranda and "Inter-Agency Committee for Minority Business Enterprise, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- The Protected Market Model: West Side Community Development Corporation- Container Corporation of America, Okie Industry Program, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- National Advisory Council on Minority Business Enterprise and Subcommittee Meetings and Agendas, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Memoranda and Letters, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Outline/Draft of Proposed Bill (Box 5, Folder 12)
- "The Waco Plan" and Breadbasket Commercial Association- Construction Division- A Program for the Development of the Construction Division (Box 5, Folder 13)
- "Urban Enterprise" Vol. 1, No. 7, "Latin America Opportunities and Responsibilities"- Gallagher, "What We Have Learned from Operating out Branch Stores in Mexico, Brazil, Venezuela, Columbia, Peru, Cuba, Canada, and Australia"- Address by Theodore V. Hous, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Menswear Retailers of America: Ownership Opportunities Program, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Menswear Retailers of America Newspaper No. 220 Whole No. 23240, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Sears, Roebuck in Latin America (Box 5, Folder 17)
- The Franchise Model: The Mopar Division of Chrysler Motors Corporation- Mr. Geoffrey Halverson, International Industries- Dr. Gary Cadenhead (Box 5, Folder 18)
- "International Marketing"- A Presentation by John Gallagher, News Clippings and Articles, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Meetings Between the Unions- Contractors- Builders and the Coalition for United Community Action- Mayor Richard J. Daley, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Agreement, Proposals, and Drafts between the Chicago and Cook County Building Trades Council, The Building Construction Employers Association of Chicago, and the Coalition for United Community Action, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- "The Chicago Plan": Drafts, Revisions and Related Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- National Advisory Council on Minority Business Enterprise Memoranda and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- In the Matter of Negotiations Regarding the Chicago Plan, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Stenographic Report of the Meetings Between the Union- Contactors- Builders and the Coalition and the Building Construction Employers' Association of Chicago and the Coalition, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Report of the Meeting Between the Union- Contractors- Builders and he Coalition, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Meeting Between the Unions- Contractors- Builders and the Coalition for United Community Action Nov. 5th, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Report on Meeting Between the Union- Contractors- Builders and the Coalition for United Community Action, Oct. 10th, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- James V. Byington & Associates: Productivity Analysis, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Notes and News Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Questionnaire and Report of Employee Attitude Survey Conducted at the Amsco-Excell Corporation Jamestown, New York, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Letters and Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- "Three Productive Years"- Three Year Report of the Jamestown Area Labor- Management Committee, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- "A New Economic Process" Proposal to Governor- Elect Hugh A. Carey, "Worker Motivation and Monitoring of Results", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous Papers and Pamphlets, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- "Positive Labor Relations" and News Clipping (Box 5, Folder 36)
- NULL (Box 5, Folder 37)
- NULL (Box 5, Folder 38)
- University of Strathclyde, Department of Economics, Fairfields Ltd.: Research Reports #1-2, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Fairfield and Upper Clyde News, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Post Office, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Esso Petroleum Company, Ltd., 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- British Steel Corporation, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Extract from "New Society"- The Lessons of Fawly by Allan Flanders, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- British Railways Board: Pay and Efficiency: A New Wage and Salary Structure, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)